Meticulous data scientist with extensive experience applying predictive models and statistical tests to develop key insights into data and communicating the results to audiences with varying levels of technical expertise. Outstanding critical thinker that quickly troubleshoots problems and finds solutions. Develops a fundamental understanding of the issue at hand and teaches others how to achieve the same.

Oualifications Include:

Statistics & probability • Risk Modeling • Machine learning • Deep learning • Data analysis • Natural language processing Bayesian Methods • Object-oriented programming • Python • R • SAS • SQL • Java • MATLAB • Mathematica • Javascript Shell scripting • Git • Tensorflow • Keras • Scikit-learn • Numpy • Pandas • Statsmodels • Tableau • Excel • Dask • Elasticsearch • Logstash • Kibana • Amazon Web Services • Teaching • Public Speaking • Presentations Oral & written communications • Mandarin Chinese (conversational)

Technical Skills:

- Proficient in Python, SQL, Scikit-Learn, and Keras along with object-oriented programming in general
- Knowledgable in statistics and the mathematical theory behind machine learning and deep learning algorithms
- Highly skilled in data analysis, predictive modeling, and data visualization & presentation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DSFederal – **USDA**, Greenbelt, MD

Dec 2018 - Present

Data Scientist / Government Contractor

- Set up an Elastic data pipeline and dashboard to track and link KPIs across geographically dispersed databases
- Utilized a supercomputing cluster to process the National Agricultural Library's entire corpus of research articles and train a word vector model on agricultural vocabulary
- Built an algorithm to cluster and recommend relevant research articles to agriculture datasets in NAL's catalog
- Constructed a natural language pipeline to automatically parse and structure PDFs, tag and cluster research proposals, identify potential equipment and data sharing opportunities, and display key insights graphically in an interactive dashboard

American Institute for Research, Washington, D.C.

July 2018 – Dec 2018

Math Assessment Temp

- Developed scripts to clean, parse, and categorize data from .docx reports into spreadsheets
- Created software tools to automate common tasks, e.g generating reports, emailing requests, and filling web forms
- Queried databases and generatedreports to help team members organize their work more efficiently
- Wrote and reviewed standardized math questions for state assessments for accuracy

General Assembly, Springfield, VA

January 2018 – July 2018

Instructional Associate

- Provided instructional support for General Assembly's part-time data science classes for professionals
- Assessed student projects, deliver lectures, and provided online class support to students
- · Analyzed key student metrics for success and adapted the base curriculum to address student needs
- Delivered individually tailored instruction to students who were struggling with the curriculum

EDUCATION

B.S., Mathematics, specializing in Physics, University of Maryland, College Park 2017

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Deeplearning.ai, Deep Learning Specialization, Online, 2018
- Data Science Immersive, General Assembly, Washington, D.C. 2017
- Society of Actuaries, Exam FM Financial Mathematics, 2015
- Society of Actuaries, Exam P Probability, 2014